Guide to the David Paletz Student Films, 1975-1996 UA.29.02.0239
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
David Paletz Student films
1975-1996
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Paletz, David L., 1934-
UA.29.02.0239
1 Linear Feet
The David Paletz Student Films were created by Duke students for David Paletz's POLI 130: Politics and Media course, with topics covering politics and Duke University.
Historical note
David Paletz was a professor in the Political Science department of Duke University starting in 1967 and specialized in American politics and media.
Collection Overview
The collection includes fims on seven U-matic and nine VHS cassette tapes that cover a variety of topics related to politics and Duke University.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The David Paletz Student Films were received by the University Archives as a gift in January, 2014 and in 2018.
Duke University -- Students; Duke University -- History -- 20th century; Documentary films -- United States; Duke University. Department of Political Science
- Video Cassettes, 1975-1996; 1
  - Political Events and Local Television News by Jeff Blauvelt and Cindy Lewis, 1975; 1
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA29020239_Umatic_0001)
  - Duke: Portrait of an Institution Pro-Con by Karyn Roberts and Sarah Darer, 1983; 2
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA29020239_Umatic_0002)
  - Oliver North: Covert Activity Uncovered by Jeffrey Cooper, 1988; 3
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA29020239_Umatic_0003)
  - Greek Life at Duke and Eruditio et Fraternity by Tim Haddock, 1991; 4
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA29020239_Umatic_0004)
  - Perceptions of Tranquility: Black-White Relations at Duke by Mike Goldstein, Ted Edwards, and Doug Lito, 1991; 5
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA29020239_Umatic_0005)
  - Duke Vigil of 1968 and Occupation of Allen Building of 1969 by Jana Eisinger, Rob Ross, and Eric Whitney, 1988; 6
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA29020239_VHS_0001)
  - Food for Thought by Mary Penrod, Rob Ruggiero, and Alex Hernandez, 1988; 7
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA29020239_VHS_0002)
  - Ignorance is No Excuse by Melissa Sue Widen and Ann Thompson Offutt, 1988; 8
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA29020239_VHS_0003)
  - The Indigent System in Durham by Nancy Inouye, Enid Paterson, and Stephanie Shmunes, circa 1988; 9
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA29020239_VHS_0004)
  - Mutual of Durham's Wild Kingdumb by Cheryl Dolins and Bill McCullough, 1988; 10
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA29020239_VHS_0005)
  - Duke Basketball Highlights 1992-1993 (Negative and Positive) by Travis Boozer, 11
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA29020239_VHS_0006)
  - Flipping Channels by Chris Charbonnier, 1994; 12
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA29020239_VHS_0007)
  - 60 More Minutes: A Closer Look at Race Relations at Duke University by Shane Shansbury and Danny Koenig, 1994; 13
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA29020239_VHS_0008)
  - Tramps by Greg Wilkerson and Ken Bensinger, 1996; 14
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA29020239_VHS_0009)
  - Control by Carl Kurlander, circa 1984
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA29020239-Umatic-0006)
    - Videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA29020239-Umatic-0007)
      Scope and Contents
      May or may not be related to film Control.